<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fixed on Patrick Yates</title>
    <link>http://www.patrickyates.me/fixed/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fixed on Patrick Yates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:01:17 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.patrickyates.me/fixed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://www.patrickyates.me/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:01:17 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.patrickyates.me/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My research interests are in Astrophysics.
My honours project involved developing a method for running numerical simulations of restarting radio jets from Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN).
The results from these simulations were analysed to determine how recurrent jet activity affected both the energetics and dynamics of the radio jets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A draft copy of my Honours thesis is available for download here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patrickyates.me/download/honours-thesis.pdf&#34;&gt;honours-thesis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A poster that I presented at CAASTRO is available for download here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patrickyates.me/download/restarting-jets.pdf&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.patrickyates.me/img/poster.png&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;From the numerical simulations I was able to create several movies illustrating the restarting nature of the jet, a selection of which are shown below.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9MRtKnmTOJ4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/32zNDlwLqtk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>http://www.patrickyates.me/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:01:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.patrickyates.me/presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patrickyates.me/presentations/swg3-2017&#34;&gt;SWG3 Wallaby Workshop 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.patrickyates.me/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:01:12 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.patrickyates.me/projects/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;untitled-for-the-moment&#34;&gt;Untitled for the moment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my Honours project, I developed several Python routines for analysing numerical simulation data obtained from the PLUTO simulation package. I am in the process of polishing my Python code so that I can release it as a standalone analysis library. Highlights will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplified loading of PLUTO data files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The projection of spherical data onto a Cartesian grid (2D)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The calculation of simulation energetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The calculation of luminosity for each grid cell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The production of simulated surface brightness distributions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The production of movies from a simulation for various variables: density, pressure, luminosity etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;turnt-ninja-substructio&#34;&gt;Turnt Ninja / Substructio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opcon/turnt-ninja&#34;&gt;Turnt Ninja&lt;/a&gt; is cross-platform open-source, GPLv3 licensed, procedurally generated music/rhythm game inspired by the wonderful Super Hexagon.
Turnt Ninja is written in C#, and uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opcon/substructio&#34;&gt;Substructio library&lt;/a&gt; for reusable code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quickfont&#34;&gt;QuickFont&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opcon/quickfont&#34;&gt;QuickFont&lt;/a&gt; is a cross-platform text rendering library for OpenTK.
The original version developed by James Lohr is no longer maintained, and I maintain the newer version of the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gwen-net&#34;&gt;Gwen.NET&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opcon/gwen-nolegacy-opentk-renderer&#34;&gt;Gwen.NET&lt;/a&gt; is a cross-platform GUI library for OpenTK.
Originally developed by Garry Newman and others, I maintain a version that relies on QuickFont for text rendering and uses modern OpenGL functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cync&#34;&gt;Cync&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opcon/cync&#34;&gt;Cync&lt;/a&gt; is a music synchronization application designed to be used with portable media players that have multiple storage drives, such as internal storage + a microSD card.
Cync will sync playlists across multiple storage drives, ensuring that the multiple storage drives are used efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.patrickyates.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 20:29:40 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.patrickyates.me/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Patrick Yates. I am passionate about Science and Technology, and am currently studying Astrophysics at the University of Tasmania.
I have recently completed my Bachelor of Science (Hons.) in Astrophysics, where I used numerical hydrodynamic simulations to study restarting radio jets from Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to my studies and research, I enjoy programming, and have developed and/or maintain a number of open-source libraries and programs.
The most notable include QuickFont, a text renderer for OpenTK, and Turnt Ninja, a music/rhythm game inspired by Super Hexagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My academic resume is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patrickyates.me/download/resume.pdf&#34;&gt;resume&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>